<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://schematype.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://schematype.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-07-19T15:58:31-07:00</updated>
<id>http://schematype.org/</id>
<title>SchemaType • Defining the Data Web</title>
<subtitle>A Data Type Definition Language</subtitle>
<entry>
<title>Why DSL Matters</title>
<link href="http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/08/why-dsl-matters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why DSL Matters" />
<published>2016-07-08T09:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-08T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/08/why-dsl-matters</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/08/why-dsl-matters/">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2016/07/06/schematype-basic-language-design/&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt; I gave
you an introduction to the SchemaType language. It was meant to raise questions
and I got a few. Mostly they were centered around using DSL shortcuts instead
of using pure data. In this post I’ll tell more of the SchemaType language
story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider this &lt;a href=&quot;http://json-schema.org/examples.html&quot;&gt;JSON Schema flagship
example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &quot;$schema&quot;: &quot;http://json-schema.org/draft-04/schema#&quot;,
    &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Example Schema&quot;,
    &quot;type&quot;: &quot;object&quot;,
    &quot;properties&quot;: {
        &quot;firstName&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;string&quot;
        },
        &quot;lastName&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;string&quot;
        },
        &quot;age&quot;: {
            &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Age in years&quot;,
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;integer&quot;,
            &quot;minimum&quot;: 0
        }
    },
    &quot;required&quot;: [&quot;firstName&quot;, &quot;lastName&quot;]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In SchemaType, this would look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;-spec: schematype.org/v0.0.1
-from: github:schematype/type/#v0.1.2
-desc: Example Schema
firstName: +string
lastName: +string
age?: +int 0.. --Age in years
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things come to mind. Either you love it because it is so tight, or you hate
it because it is so tight! Well don’t worry, SchemaType has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DSL syntax used above is just syntactic sugar for the more explicit syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;firstName:
  -type: string
lastName:
  -type: string
age:
  -type: int
  -min: 0
  -desc: Age in years
  -opt: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use a mix like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;firstName: +string
lastName: +string
age?:
  -: +int 0..
  -desc: Age in years
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;code&gt;age&lt;/code&gt; field we use the DSL for the type and &lt;code&gt;min&lt;/code&gt; constraint. These go
under the special &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; key which indicates DSL is in the value. This is needed
since the outer value is an object now, instead of a single YAML string value.
Then we use the explicit &lt;code&gt;-desc&lt;/code&gt; for the description field. You might find that
this form looks best in your schema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that in the more explicit example above, there is still some DSL; namely
the &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; in front of the SchemaType keywords. Of course we can work out other
ways to turn that into data too, but then we approach looking like JSON Schema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is to make these documents, which can become massive in size,
readable and maintainable. What happens when the schema you are defining has an
object with keys like “type”, “description” and “required”? Well you have to
figure out what level you are at to determine whether they are for your schema
or for JSON Schema. With SchemaType, everything is instantly recognizable
because of the DSL features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the main point that I want to convey in this post. For SchemaType to
become popular it not only needs to be extremely powerful, it needs to have a
flexible syntax so that people actually like working with it. You might have
noticed that even though SchemaType is a YAML based format, none of the YAML
quoting styles are ever used. This is on purpose. YAML only requires quoting
when the first character is a space or YAML syntax character, or when there is
a &lt;code&gt;_#&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:_&lt;/code&gt; sequence in the string. The SchemaType DSL syntax is careful to
avoid these so that you can use unquoted strings for everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One nice thing about the SchemaType syntax is that you don’t need to decide up
front which style to use. The &lt;code&gt;schematype&lt;/code&gt; CLI can reformat your schema files
for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ schematype format --compact some.stp
$ schematype format --explicit some.stp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, SchemaType schemas get compiled before they are used. All the external
references are pulled in and tied together into one big and very explicit data
structure that is even more unreadable than JSON Schema. You never need to look
at these files unless you are debugging something. When you publish a
SchemaType schema, you are encouraged to publish the compiled form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ schematype compile --sign some.stp -o some.stx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create a digitally signed compiled schema file, that other schema
types will use when they reference your hosted schema. &lt;code&gt;.stx&lt;/code&gt; is the SchemaType
extension for a compiled schema. It is actually stored as compact JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stay-tuned&quot;&gt;Stay Tuned&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written a few blog posts this week to give you an idea of where SchemaType
is headed as a language and as a software development framework. The next
things I’ll be working on are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SchemaType Language Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;schematype&lt;/code&gt; CLI tool
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;compile&lt;/code&gt; a SchemaType schema file to the canonical immutable form&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; a SchemaType file from an existing JSON Schema file&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;export&lt;/code&gt; a SchemaType file to a JSON Schema file&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;validate&lt;/code&gt; a data file against a schema file&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;generate&lt;/code&gt; various software components. Examples:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Go lang data structs&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;HTML input form&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;SQL schema file&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Protobuf message definition&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Swagger v2 schema definitions&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start the SchemaType v0.0.1 specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/help/&quot;&gt;Please join me&lt;/a&gt; if you have ideas to contribute or just want to play
along. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Ingy döt Net&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<author>
<name>ingydotnet</name>
</author>
<summary></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>SchemaType Basic Language Design</title>
<link href="http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/06/schematype-basic-language-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SchemaType Basic Language Design" />
<published>2016-07-06T09:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-06T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/06/schematype-basic-language-design</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/06/schematype-basic-language-design/">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2016/07/05/schematype-can-you-define-that/&quot;&gt;yesterday’s post&lt;/a&gt; I
talked in broad terms about the scope, purpose and intention of SchemaType
without actually showing what the language looks like.  In this post I’ll fix
that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assume you have this &lt;code&gt;person.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;name: Ingy döt Net
age: 17
dead: false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to define a &lt;code&gt;person.stp&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;.stp&lt;/code&gt; is the SchemaType file
extension) file might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;name: string
age: integer
dead: boolean
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the starting point of SchemaType. Let’s talk about what we have so far.
First off the overall input format for SchemaType is YAML. Note that since JSON
is a proper subset of YAML, you could also write SchemaType files in JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of an object is simply a mapping of its keys to the &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; of
its value. This is very simple (which is good), but it’s too simple to be a
real language. Let’s move forward with a few additions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;-name: /person
-desc: Data about a person
-spec: schematype.org/v0.0.1
-from: github:schematype/type/#v0.1.6

name: +human/name
age: +int 1..100
dead?: +boolean
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a valid and complete SchemaType definition. You could publish this
file for reuse at &lt;code&gt;http://yourdomain.net/person.stp&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you probably noticed are the unusual punctuation characters
like &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt;. SchemaType is a &lt;em&gt;YAML based &lt;strong&gt;DSL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The intention
of the DSL is to keep the definitions concise. At the expense of learning just
a few syntax concepts, you can keep simple things simple and massive things
manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keys that begin with a &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; belong to the SchemaType language. The first 4 keys
will be present in almost every SchemaType definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;-name&lt;/code&gt; field refers to the name of the type being defined in this file. It
should match the base name of the file that it is stored in. A SchemaType file
can define multiple types. In that case the name should be set to &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; and the
file name should be &lt;code&gt;index.stp&lt;/code&gt;. A condensed example of an &lt;code&gt;index.stp&lt;/code&gt; file
that defines the types &lt;code&gt;type1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;type2&lt;/code&gt; would look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-name: /
+type1: ...
+type2: ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly the &lt;code&gt;...&lt;/code&gt; is actually SchemaType syntax. It denotes a type
reference of &lt;code&gt;+any&lt;/code&gt;, ie any type. More about that in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;-desc&lt;/code&gt; field is a short description of the purpose of this schema. The
&lt;code&gt;-spec&lt;/code&gt; field indicates the version of the SchemaType Language Specification
being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important keyword here is &lt;code&gt;from&lt;/code&gt;. Within a SchemaType definition,
types are referenced by names preceded with a &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. In reality, each &lt;code&gt;+type1&lt;/code&gt;
reference expands to a full URL like
&lt;code&gt;https://github.com/schematype/type/blob/f54b0aa/type1&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;-from&lt;/code&gt; is a set
of type shorthands to their immutable definition URLs. Again, more about that
in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the meat of our SchemaType example from above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;name: +human/name
age: +int 1..100
dead?: +boolean
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a SchemaType definition that uses &lt;code&gt;+string&lt;/code&gt; it should be a red flag
that the schema author is DoingItWrong™. The &lt;code&gt;+human/name&lt;/code&gt; type (defined by
&lt;code&gt;schematype/type&lt;/code&gt;) inherits from &lt;code&gt;+string&lt;/code&gt; but it places much more strict
constraints on valid values. For instance a URL or a GUID or the full text of
the US Constitution are all valid strings but will not be valid names of
people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SchemaType is very big on type &lt;strong&gt;inheritance&lt;/strong&gt;. SchemaType only defines 5 types
in its spec: &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Number&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Null&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Any&lt;/code&gt;, but none of
these are ever referenced directly in schemas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next consider the &lt;code&gt;age&lt;/code&gt; field. This is actually creating a new temporary or
anonymous type. It inherits from &lt;code&gt;+int&lt;/code&gt; but then places a range constraint on
it. Another way to do this would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;name: +human/name
age: +age
dead?: +boolean

+age: +int 1..100
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference here is that we named the subtype. It is therefore available
publicly as &lt;code&gt;person/age&lt;/code&gt; in our schema publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, but certainly not least is the &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; n &lt;code&gt;dead?&lt;/code&gt;. It simply means that the
&lt;code&gt;dead&lt;/code&gt; key/value pair is optional. This implies the &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;age&lt;/code&gt; are
required. And that’s true. All keys in a definition are required by default.
This stands in contrast to JSON Schema where all pairs are optional by default
and unspecified keys are allowed. To allow any extra key/value pair in
SchemaType you need to declare it like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;name: +human/name
age: +int 1..100
dead?: +boolean
...: ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s that &lt;code&gt;...&lt;/code&gt; again. This means that any key is allowed to map to any
value type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That wraps up the explanation of a very basic SchemaType document. For
comparison, let’s look at the JSON Schema equivalent of our example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;{
    &quot;$schema&quot;: &quot;http://json-schema.org/draft-04/schema#&quot;,
    &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Person&quot;,
    &quot;type&quot;: &quot;object&quot;,
    &quot;properties&quot;: {
        &quot;name&quot;: {
            &quot;$ref&quot;: &quot;https://example.com/json.schema#human/name&quot;
        },
        &quot;age&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;integer&quot;,
            &quot;minimum&quot;: 1,
            &quot;maximum&quot;: 100
        },
        &quot;dead&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;boolean&quot;
        }
    },
    &quot;additionalProperties&quot;: false,
    &quot;required&quot;: [
      &quot;name&quot;,
      &quot;age&quot;
    ]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;em&gt;rough&lt;/em&gt; equivalent. This example is not so bad because you can see
the whole thing on one page. In reality, JSON Schema gets unwieldy fast. A
primary reason is that things like &lt;code&gt;required&lt;/code&gt; are not made known in the place
where the key is defined. I’ve seen many files where that information is 1000s
of lines apart. The other thing is that it is hard to tell what parts are the
JSON Schema language words and what parts are the data you are defining.
SchemaType tries to make all this easy, compact and less painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is an introduction to the language basics. It was intended to raise
more questions than it answers. There is much more to cover, but hopefully
that’s enough to start you thinking about SchemaType!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<author>
<name>ingydotnet</name>
</author>
<summary></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>SchemaType! Can you define that for me?</title>
<link href="http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/05/schematype-can-you-define-that/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SchemaType! Can you define that for me?" />
<published>2016-07-05T09:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-05T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/05/schematype-can-you-define-that</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://schematype.org/news/2016/07/05/schematype-can-you-define-that/">&lt;p&gt;SchemaType is a new definition language for data. More specifically the data
formats of the web that don’t already have definitions. Formats like YAML, JSON
and CSV. Basically any format where the data is (or can be) represented as
“objects”; ie mappings of known string keys to typed values. There’s more to
the language of course, but defining objects is certainly a core principle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SchemaType, as the name implies, defines &lt;strong&gt;schemas&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;types&lt;/strong&gt;. Effectively
schemas and types are the same thing: named structural and semantic definitions
of data points. The word “type” is usually applied to single values; things
like “string”, “integer”, “boolean” and “date”. The term “schema”, on the other
hand, is applied to data collection types; things like “address”, which might
be composed of “street”, “city”, “state”, and “postal-code”. The SchemaType
language is concerned with the definitions of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;define-the-data-web-by-2018&quot;&gt;Define the Data Web by 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SchemaType project would like to define all open, undefined data in the
next 2 years. This is a lofty goal, but the return on investment is grand, as
I’ll try to show. Also, it turns out that schema can be substantially generated
from valid data, so the data of the web could be crawled and a massive set of
schemas could be started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would this be useful though? Glad you asked. It is my belief that software
development is moving away from people writing code, and having computers write
(generate) code from data. Writing and maintaining the same kinds of code for
every data source in many programming languages becomes infeasible. There are
many types of code that can be written for you, and written better and faster
and more continuously than any human possibly could. If you accept this logic,
then the only programming left to do is writing the code that generates more
code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we are a long ways off from replacing software development with code
generation, but we can make inroads immediately. What’s missing? Well the
biggest missing part is accurately defined data, ie &lt;strong&gt;Schema&lt;/strong&gt;. Schema needs a
language that can move beyond basic validation, and provide richer semantic
info (I like to call them “hints”) on what code should be generated in various
contexts. For instance, declaring that an object property is a “string” is
fairly useless. Saying that it is a multi line, printable unicode text
paragraph (which happens to inherit from string), can provide an input UI
generator with the right hint to make a good UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the kinds of code that generation I see Schema helping make
possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data validation (obviously)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End user input UI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data visualization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test data generation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Language specific “typedef” code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translators between formats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RDBMS modeling and SQL generation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protobuf definition generators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll talk more about each of these points in upcoming posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-schematype&quot;&gt;Why SchemaType?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the creators of YAML, I have known for a decade that Schema is the
next big effort. It seems that now, in the middle of 2016, all the stars have
aligned, the mass has become critical and time is ripe for SchemaType.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON Schema is the closest effort to compare SchemaType to. It has gained some
acceptance in various places but seems to have stalled out in forward progress.
Still it is a good starting point to research, as much time has been invested
in it. I believe SchemaType will offer at least these advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simpler to author, read and maintain
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JSON Schema gets too complex too quickly&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SchemaType docs look closer to the data they are defining&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to publish and share important schemas
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Like GitHub, &lt;em&gt;forking&lt;/em&gt; schemas is a good thing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leverage ready-made code generation tools
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SchemaType will have an ever growing set of tools&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide type/schema definition immutability
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Schemas import other schemas at specific commit points&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide digital signing to published open types
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Know, verify and trust the sources of your import schemas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Promote multiple authorities of trust
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Anyone can define, host, fork the base schemas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SchemaType will consider I18N issues from the get-go&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get things rolling with SchemaType, early implementations will be able to
not only import JSON Schema to SchemaType but also to export SchemaType
definitions back to JSON Schema. Therefore if you are already invested in JSON
Schema, it will be easy to either make the switch, or simply use the more
expressive and elegant SchemaType and then save it back to JSON Schema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;join-the-schema-revolution&quot;&gt;Join The Schema Revolution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong type definitions for simple open data sources, combined with code
generators for the common parts of software development is the future; and you
can help bring it about sooner. SchemaType will be defined and implemented in
the open. If you are interested please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.schematype.org/help/&quot;&gt;join us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours truly, Ingy döt Net.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<author>
<name>ingydotnet</name>
</author>
<summary></summary>
</entry>
</feed>
